Support for NPR music comes from Capital
One, proud supporters of NPR music and
the Tiny Desk Contest. What's in your
wallet? Learn more at capitalone.com.
>> There's mosquitoes on the river.
Fish are rising up like birds.
It's been hot for seven weeks now, too.
Hot to even speak now. Did you hear what
I just heard?
Well, it may have been a fiddle.
Or it could have been the wind.
But that seems to be a beat now. I can
feel it in my feet now. Listen, here it
comes again.
There's a beat now
over the highway.
They're hot stepping into town.
It's a
rainbow full of sound.
It's fireworks, lyre birds, and clowns.
Everybody is dancing.
Come on, children. Come on, children.
Come on, clap your hands.
Well, the song went down in honey.
And the moon came up like wine.
You know, the stars were spinning dizzy.
You know, they kept the band so busy. We
both got about the time.
They'll ban me on description.
Like Jehovah's choir.
People joining hand in hand while the
music played the band
long as setting us on fire.
Crazy rooster crowing midnight.
Buzz of lightning roll along.
Old men sing about their dreams. Women
laughing, children scream and the band
kept playing on.
Keep on dancing till the daylight.
Greet the morning
ever so long.
No one noticed but the bands all packed
and gone.
Will they ever hear it all?
And they kept on dancing.
Come on, children. Come on, children.
Come on, clap your hands.
Well, the cool breezes came on Tuesday.
And the pawns took on the pride.
And the fields were full of dancing,
full of singing and romancing. The music
never stopped.
>> That one's for Bobby. Um we are the Pan
Detroit Ensemble and we are on a mission
to promulgate the indigenous sounds of
our hometown of Detroit, Michigan. You
dig?
Say hello TO THE MIGHTY STEPHANIE
Christian on vocals.
And that was Professor Vincent Chandler
ON THE DRUMS.
ALL RIGHT. HERE'S AN ORIGINAL SONG FROM
OUR NEW album that's called You Asked, I
Came.
>> 1 2 3 4
>> As Blue Note recording artist Dave
McMurray ON THE SAXOPHONE.
HERE'S ANOTHER ONE FROM NEW RECORDS
CALLED Midnight Marauders.
>> 1 2 3 4
>> Take my eyes that I could be so blind
that I could not see.
You were there
waiting.
Lost and found the second time around.
Work all day up to the night and find
your way home.
Night marauder, you will never walk
alone.
The time has come for us to leave the
problems of the day and I would not
waste a moment. No way.
Went to the corner store to buy me some
cigarettes and some papers. When the
girl at the counter caught my
and asked me to meet the litter to set
down at the bar at the back of the
store. A place where you can lay.
Oh, place in your order
with me now.
Oh, we are the midnight marauders
here.
Oh, WE HAVE COME TO SET YOU FREE.
We are the midnight
marauders. We have come to set you free.
We have come to set you free.
Yeah.
>> YEAH.
>> WOO!
>> THANK YOU.
THAT'S WAYNE GERARD ON THE GUITAR.
ON the percussion, MAHINDI MESSIAH.
AND OVER HERE ON THE DRUMS, gluing our
groove together, the great Jeff Canady.
Uh here's a Hank Williams song.
>> 1
2 3
>> Little girl, if you're feeling low and
you've got no place to go.
Just give me a ring.
And some junk
I'll bring.
Well, cuz
I
ain't got nothing but time.
Baby,
I ain't got nothing but time.
I
ain't got nothing but time.
Baby,
you can call me anytime.
If you say so, we'll stay all night.
Don't worry about what's on the ride.
And anytime you want to go
Oh, well, baby,
just let me know.
Now, baby, just come on and smile and
you'll find that life is still worth a
while.
And if you took the time to look
Oh, my number
Oh, it's in the book.
Cuz
I ain't got nothing but time.
Baby,
you can call me anytime.
Well.
Oh.
>> Thank you.
>> All right.
That That's John Douglas on the TRUMPET
OVER HERE.
AND HERSCHEL BOONE AND TARANA Boone on
the harmony vocals.
It's been a real honor to play behind
this desk for you today. Thank you very
much for having us.
This last one features our brilliant
keyboard player, Louis Resto.
>> I hear you coming, you're surrounding
me.
I try to fight it, just you wait and
see.
Cuz when you come around, you send me
right into space.
I get excited and I start to go insane,
insane.
Take my feet up off the ground.
Yeah, every time you come around.
Help me, help me.
Why don't you help me out?
Insane.
I saw three women just the other day,
and I snuck up too close to hear what
they had to say. They said that Rudolph
Valentino's the best lover in town,
and when I need him most, he ain't
around.
Hey fellas.
I need some more support.
Cuz when she do me like she do, I wind
up in a rut, and that rut, you see,
makes living hard for me.
If this goes on much longer, I'll lose
my identity.
Take my feet up off the ground.
Every time you come around.
Yeah.
Insane.
>> Insane.
Oh,
oh, insane.
Insane.
Yeah.
Thank you.
>> Thanks for watching. Support for NPR
Music comes from Rivian, makers of
all-electric adventure vehicles,
including the R1S three-row SUV. More at
rivian.com.